{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Which of the following characteristic of the Rotavirus was important for the construction of the Rotashield vaccine?", "opta": "The possession of a segmented RNA genome", "optb": "A limited number of capsule types", "optc": "The ability of monkey Rotavirus strains to cause serious illness (diarrhea) in human beings", "optd": "The ability of the Rotavirus to be transmitted faster", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Plastic implants can pose a serious nosocomial infection problem because", "opta": "phagocytes have trouble moving on the plastic surface", "optb": "phagocytes have trouble engulfing bacteria embedded in a biofilm", "optc": "infected implants usually have to be surgically removed", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A major difference between EHEC and EPEC is", "opta": "EHEC secretes a Shiga-like toxin and EPEC does not", "optb": "EHEC possesses a type III secretion system and EPEC does not", "optc": "EPEC rearranges host cell actin and EHEC does not", "optd": "EPEC passes through the placenta to infect the fetus and EHEC does not", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The nature of the poliovirus gives for oral vaccination (satin vaccine) as part of the eradication programme is", "opta": "heat killed virus", "optb": "live attenuated strains of all three immunological types", "optc": "small dosage of wild-type live viruses", "optd": "formalin-inactivated viruses", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is true regarding anthrax?", "opta": "Anthrax is caused by a virus", "optb": "Anthrax is highly contagious", "optc": "Inhalation anthrax and cutaneous anthrax are caused by separate strains of Bacillus anthracis", "optd": "Inhalation Anthrax requires infection with a large number of spores", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The toxins produced by bacteria", "opta": "kill viruses", "optb": "encourage bacterial reproduction", "optc": "interfere with physiological processes in the body", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pseudomembraneous colitis is", "opta": "precipitated by the use of certain antibiotics", "optb": "caused by a gram-positive bacterium", "optc": "caused by a spore-forming bacterium", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Both Mycobacterium tuberculosis and Streptococcus pneumoniae", "opta": "are acquired by inhalation", "optb": "have cell walls that contain a high content of mycolic acids", "optc": "have polysaccharide capsules", "optd": "stay in the lung and rarely, if ever, enter the bloodstream", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Cholera toxin is an A-B type toxin in which the B portions bind to a receptor on a host cell and the A portion enters the cell to cause", "opta": "ADP ribosylation of adenylate cyclase that stops production of cAMP", "optb": "ADP ribosylation of a G protein that locks it into an active form that stimulates adenylate cyclase to make cAMP", "optc": "cleavage of rRNA that results in disruption of ribosome function", "optd": "ADP ribosylation of guanylate cyclase that stimulates production of cGMP", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Mucus helps in protecting against pathogens by", "opta": "lowering the pH", "optb": "facilitating the growth of normal flora", "optc": "blocking access and attachment of pathogens to mucosal surfaces", "optd": "sequestering Iron", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Type III secretion systems are used to inject \"effector\" proteins directly into a host cell. Salmonella uses a type III secretion system to help the pathogen to", "opta": "survive the acid pH of the stomach", "optb": "secrete LT (heat labile toxin) and ST (heat stable toxin) into the lumen of the intestine", "optc": "survive within macrophages", "optd": "activate T cells to proliferate and secrete cytokines", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of these cytokines is also known under the name cachectin?", "opta": "Interferon gamma", "optb": "Interleukin 2", "optc": "Tumor necrosis factor (TNF)", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is not a major defense mechanism in the stomach?", "opta": "Proteolytic enzymes", "optb": "Low pH", "optc": "Dense normal flora", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The agent responsible for causing mad cow disease is thought to be a", "opta": "fungus", "optb": "protozoan", "optc": "prion", "optd": "virus", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The \"A\" subunit of diphtheria toxin", "opta": "binds host cell receptors found on heart cells", "optb": "cause ADP ribosylation of a factor involved in protein synthesis", "optc": "forms cAMP that leads to fluid accumulation", "optd": "lysis macrophages with the release of cytokines", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Coxsackie virus B3, a subgroup of enteroviruses, commonly causes", "opta": "acute hemorrhagic conjunctivitis", "optb": "muscular dystrophy", "optc": "myocarditis", "optd": "gastroenteritis", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Prontosil is", "opta": "an effective antibacterial when used in animals", "optb": "an effective antibacterial when used in in-vitro cultures", "optc": "an effective antibacterial both in animals as well as in in-vitro cultures", "optd": "not used as an antibacterial agent", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "All infections do not cause fever and all fevers are not due to infections which of the following is an example of non-infections cause of fever?", "opta": "Typhoid", "optb": "Chicken pox", "optc": "Rheumatic disease", "optd": "Malaria", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Immunization with which of the following toxoid induces high titer serum antibody, but does not protect from the corresponding disease?", "opta": "Tetanus", "optb": "Botulism", "optc": "Diphtheria", "optd": "Shigellosis", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statements is not true regarding Mycobacterium tuberculosis and/or the disease it causes?", "opta": "The pathogen contains mycolic acid in its cell wall", "optb": "The pathogen can live inside macrophages", "optc": "Antibodies to the pathogen are protective", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is common in catheters and ventilators?", "opta": "They bypass important defenses of the body", "optb": "Bacteria responsible for associated infections are usually susceptible to antibiotics", "optc": "They predispose patients to viral rather than bacterial infections", "optd": "They are used primarily in neonatal intensive care units", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An important host defense of human beings is a dense resident microbiota associated with", "opta": "lungs", "optb": "bladder", "optc": "uterus", "optd": "vagina", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Lactoferrin helps to protect against pathogens by", "opta": "sequestering Iron", "optb": "blocking sebum production", "optc": "lowering the pH", "optd": "facilitating the growth of normal flora", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The influenza vaccine is administered each year because", "opta": "mutations in the viral hemagglutinin may allow the virus to evade the immune response elicited by previous vaccines", "optb": "it is a polysaccharide vaccine that does not confer long-term protection", "optc": "the vaccine is sufficiently toxic to make it necessary to administer only a small amount at any one time", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following disease is caused by DNA viruses?", "opta": "Poliomyelitis", "optb": "Yellow fever", "optc": "Measles", "optd": "Small pox", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is common in the disease caused by Coryne-bacterium diphtheriae and Bacillus anthracis?", "opta": "Both organisms are gram-positive spore formers", "optb": "Diphtheria toxin and edema toxin are ADP ribosylating toxins", "optc": "The most serious disease symptoms are the direct result of toxin action", "optd": "Both organisms cause skin and respiratory tract infections", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Fatalities following influenza infection are usually due to the", "opta": "dehydration", "optb": "bacterial superinfection", "optc": "damage to the heart muscle", "optd": "formation of granulomas in the lung", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following disease is not caused by microbial protein toxin?", "opta": "Botulism", "optb": "Diphtheria", "optc": "Shigella dysentery", "optd": "Tuberculosis", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the human disease cholera, what is it that actually ends up killing the victim?", "opta": "Faulty carrier proteins", "optb": "Dehydration and loss of nutrients", "optc": "Too little water in the food stream", "optd": "the toxin produced by the bacterium", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Each of the 3 virulence factors of Bacillus anthracis i.e. the capsule, edema toxin and lethal toxin can affect the activity of", "opta": "B cells", "optb": "macrophages", "optc": "ciliated epithelial cells", "optd": "M cells", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}